TV를 볼 때에는 밝은 방에서 적당히 떨어져서 보도록 해!
While you're watching the television...
Selama menonton acara ini
...be sure to keep your distance and watch in a well-lit room!
pastikan berada di jarak yang cukup dan di ruangan yang terang!
Plan
Webdiver Production Committee
Original Plan
Ishikawa Hiroto
Dennou Boukenki
Series Composition
Chief Director
Sekijima Mayori
Okajima Kunitoshi
Character Design
Takahashi Naruyo
Concept Design
Color Scheme
Moriki Yasuhiro
Kawami Takuya
Production Designer
Director of Audiography
Composite Director
Iwase Eiji
Tanaka Hideyuki
Nagaushi Yutaka
Music
Music Producer
Music Collaboration
Hayashi Yuzo
Kumada Kazuo
Television Tokyo Music
Opening Theme
Lyrics
Composer/Arrangement
Oikawa Neko
Hirama Akihiko
Song
Columbia Japan
Production Collaboration
Animation Production
Animation Producer
AEON (We've)
Kachihide Yuki
Nomura Hiroshi
Producer
Iwata Makiko (TV Tokyo)
Yamazaki Tatsuji
Director
Negishi Hiroshi
Production
다이탈리온과 전투 중, 글라디온은 갑자기 켄토를 다이버랜드에 돌려보냈다.
During the battle against Ditalion, Gladion suddenly sent Kento back to Diverland.
Di tengah pertarungan melawan Ditalion, tiba-tiba Gladion mengembalikan Kento ke Diverland.
켄토의 아버지 타케토와 아우 카이토가 다이탈리온의 몸 안에 갇혀버렸기 때문이다.
This is because Kento's father Taketo and younger brother Kaito were captured inside Ditalion's body.
Itu karena ayah Kento, Taketo, dan Kaito ditawan di dalam tubuh Ditalion.
켄토는 아오이, 쟌, 나오키의 도움으로 네오다이브 시스템으로 다시 한번 매지컬 스테이션에 가려고 하지만,
Kento tries to go to Magical Station once again using Neodive System with Aoi, Jean, Naoki's help,
Dengan bantuan Aoi, Jean dan Naoki, Kento bermaksud untuk kembali ke Magical Station dengan sistem Neodive
아리스가와 박사가 발견하고 만다.
but Prof. Arisugawa finds it out.
tapi ketahuan oleh Prof. Arisugawa.
다이탈리온의 사악한 기운의 폭탄으로 다이버랜드가 폭파하기까지 4시간.
4 hours until Diverland explodes by Ditalion's evil aura bomb.
Tinggal 4 jam lagi sebelum bom energi jahat Ditalion menghancurkan Diverland.
켄토는 결국 자신의 비밀을 드러냈다.
At last, Kento had to reveal his secret.
Akhirnya, Kento pun mengakui rahasia dirinya.
시간의 신전! 재회로의 다이브
Temple of Time!
Dive of Reunion
Kuil Waktu!
Dive Menuju Pertemuan Kembali
뭐! 켄토 군. 네가 글라디온과?
That's impossible! Kento, you and Gladion?
Mustahil! Kento, kau dan Gladion?
저는, 저하고 글라디온이, 오늘까지 함께 데리트로스하고 싸워 왔어요.
I... Gladion and I has been fighting together against Deletloss up until today.
Aku... Aku dan Gladion terus bertarung bersama melawan Deletloss sampai hari ini juga.
지금 글라디온이 다이탈리온과 결판을 보고 있어요.
Now, Gladion is having his last battle against Ditalion.
Sekarang Gladion sedang melakukan pertempuran terakhirnya melawan Ditalion.
저는 매지컬 게이트에 돌아가야만 해요. 글라디온이 절 기다리고 있어요!
I must go back into Magical Gate. Gladion is waiting for me!
Aku harus kembali lagi ke Magical Gate. Gladion sedang menungguku di sana!
인간과 웹나이트의 융합. 믿을 수가 없군. 설마 그럴 리가.
The unification between a human and a Webknight? I cannot believe this. Such thing couldn't exist.
Kerja sama antara manusia dan Webknight? Aku tidak percaya. Mana mungkin ada hal seperti itu.
정말이에요! 데리트로스로부터 지금까지 매지컬 게이트를 되찾아낸 건 켄토하고 글라디온이 힘을 합했기 때문이에요.
He's not lying! We could recover Magical Gate from Deletloss only because of Kento and Gladion's power.
Itu benar! Magical Gate bisa direbut kembali dari tangan Deletloss.
Itu semua karena adanya kekuatan Kento dan Gladion.
저나 코우지, 마모루, 그리고 다른 아이들 모두 구해준 건 켄토하고 글라디온이에요!
It's Kento and Gladion who saved all of us, including Kouji, Mamoru, and me!
Yang menyelamatkan aku, Kouji dan Mamoru, dan juga yang lainnya adalah Kento dan Gladion!
할아버지, 제발! 켄토가 가게 해줘!
Grandpa, please! Let Kento go!
Aku mohon, Kakek! Biarkan Kento pergi!
-모두!
-아오이.
-Everyone!
-Aoi.
-Teman-teman!
알겠다. 켄토를 믿어 주지.
I understand. I'll trust in what Kento said.
Aku mengerti. Aku akan berikan kepercayaan pada Kento.
-그럼,
-그래도 매지컬 게이트에 가는 건 안 된다.
-Then...
-But,
-Jadi...
-Tapi,
that doesn't mean I'm letting you to go to Magical Gate.
bukan berarti aku memberikan ijin ke Magical Gate.
어째서?
How come?
Kenapa?
이 네오다이브 시스템으로 널 전송하고 나면 너는 다이탈리온과 직접 싸우게 된다.
If we transfer you with this Neodive Sytem, you'll have to fight against Ditalion.
Kalau kau pergi ke sana menggunakan Neodive System, maka kau akan bertarung dengan Ditalion.
-그렇게 위험한 곳으로 가는 건,
-저하고 글라디온이 함께하지 않으면,
-I can't let you face such danger--
-If Gladion and I don't combine our powers,
-Itu sangat berbahaya.
-Kalau aku dan Gladion tidak menyatukan kekuatan,
다이탈리온을 쓰러뜨릴 수 없어요! 사악한 기운의 폭탄을 막고 아빠하고 카이토를 구해야만 해요!
we can't defeat Ditalion! I must stop the evil aura bomb and save dad and Kaito!
Ditalion tidak bisa ditundukkan!
Aku ingin menghentikan bom energi jahat dan menyelamatkan Ayah serta Kaito!
-그래봤자...!
-저도 부탁드립니다.
-Even so...
-I ask for your permission as well.
-Tapi...
-Aku juga mohon dengan sangat.
어머님.
Mom...
Ibu...
이야기는 전부 들었습니다. 부탁입니다, 박사님.
I've heard everything. Please, Prof. Arisugawa.
Aku sudah mendengar semuanya. Aku mohon, Profesor Arisugawa.
-그래도, 어머님.
-저도 켄토가 위험을 무릅쓰고 있다는 건 알고 있습니다.
-But, ma'am.
-I don't want to let Kento face such danger as well.
-Tapi maaf, Nyonya.
-Sebenarnya,
aku juga tidak ingin membiarkan Kento menghadapi bahaya.
그래도 저는 이 아이를 믿어요.
But I trust in this boy.
Tapi, aku percaya pada anak ini.
켄토는 한번 결정하면 끝까지 밀고 나갈 아이에요.
Kento is a type of person who would finish something he has decided on until the end.
Kento adalah anak yang kalau sudah memutuskan sesuatu, pasti akan melakukannya sampai akhir.
-그러니까, 꼭!
-박사님!      -할아버지!
-That's why, he'll definitely...
-Professor!       -Grandpa!
-Karena itu, dia...
-Profesor!        -Kakek!
그럼 그렇게 하지요.
If you say so.
Baiklah.
-켄토 군. 잘 부탁한다.
-네!
-Kento, I'm leaving it to you.
-Of course!
-Kento, aku mohon bantuanmu.
-Iya!
작업을 서둘러라! 켄토 군의 글라디온 컨트롤러와 네오다이브 시스템을 연결해라!
Hurry up linking up Kento's Gladion Controller with Neodive System!
Cepat sedikit! Hubungkan Gladion Controller milik Kento dengan Neodive System!
폭파까지 2시간밖에 없네.
Only two hours until explosion.
Cuma tinggal 2 jam sebelum ledakan terjadi.
글라디온. 대체 왜 날 다이버랜드에 돌려 보낸 거야?
Gladion, why would you send me back to Diverland?
Gladion, kenapa kau mengembalikan aku ke Diverland?
-켄토. 켄토, 들려뾰꼬?
-카론.
-Kento. Do you hear me-pyoko?
-Karon.
-Kento? Kau dengan aku-pyoko?
-카론, 글라디온은?
-다이탈리온 앞에서 옴짝달싹 못하고 있어뾰꼬.
-Karon, how's Gladion doing?
-He cannot move a bit in front of Ditalion-pyoko.
-Karon, bagaimana Gladion?
-Gladion tidak berkutik menghadapi Ditalion-pyoko.
문제라도 있나, 글라디온? 그걸로 날 벨 생각이 없는 건가?
What's wrong, Gladion? Don't you want to slice me up with that?
Ada apa, Gladion? Bukankah kau ingin membelahku?
비겁하군, 다이탈리온!
How cowardly of you, Ditalion!
Kau pengecut, Ditalion!
나는 시간의 신. 나에게 대드는 가련한 자는 사라지는 게 낫다.
I am the god of time. Feel the result of your idiocy who dares to defy me.
Aku adalah dewa waktu. Rasakan akibat kebodohanmu yang telah berani menentangku.
글라디온이? 아냐, 곧 괜찮아질 거야! 곧 내가 갈게!
Gladion is? It's going to be fine though! I'm going there soon!
Gladion tidak berkutik? Tapi jangan khawatir! Aku akan segera ke sana!
오면 안 돼용. 글라디온은 켄토가 오는 걸 바라지 않아뾰꼬.
You shouldn't come-pyoko. Gladion does not want Kento to come here-pyoko.
Kau tidak boleh ke sini-pyoko. Gladion tidak ingin kau datang-pyoko.
-아니, 뭔 소리야?
-여기 온다고 해봤자,
-What are you talking about, Karon?
-Even if you come,
-Hah? Kau ini bicara apa, Karon?
-Biarpun kau datang,
글라디온은 또 켄토를 돌려보내버릴 거야뾰꼬.
Gladion will definitely send you back again-pyoko.
Gladion pasti akan memulangkanmu-pyoko.
그러니까 왜?
But why?!
Tapi kenapa?!
켄토가 괴롭지 않게 하기 위해서뾰꼬.
Because he doesn't want you to feel terrible-pyoko.
Karena dia tidak mau membuatmu sedih-pyoko.
-내가 괴로워진다고?
-그 때,
-Feel terrible?
-At that time,
-Membuatku sedih?
-Saat itu,
빅토리 참!
Victory Slash!
글라디온은 다이탈리온 안에 갇힌 사람을 봤어뾰꼬.
Gladion saw people trapped inside Ditalion's body-pyoko.
Gladion melihat manusia di dalam tubuh Ditalion-pyoko.
그 사람들은 켄토의 아버지하고 카이토뾰꼬.
Those people are your dad and Kaito-pyoko.
Itu adalah ayah Kento dan Kaito-pyoko.
뭐라고? 아빠뿐만이 아니라 카이토까지?
What? Not only dad, but Kaito too?
Apa? Bukan hanya ayah, tapi juga Kaito?
-그런!
-이대로 사악한 기운의 폭탄을 막고,
-No way!
-If he stops the bomb
-Astaga!
-Kalau Gladion menghancurkan Ditalion
다이버랜드를 구할 생각만으로 다이탈리온을 쓰러뜨리면 아버지하고 카이토가 함께...
and takes Ditalion down just to save Diverland, your dad and Kaito won't make it.
dan menghentikan bomnya untuk menyelamatkan Diverland, maka ayahmu dan Kaito akan...
-인질을 잡다니...
-다이탈리온 비겁하군!
-He took them as hostages?
-That's low, Ditalion!
-Dia menyandera mereka?
-Ditalion benar-benar pengecut!
그러니까 글라디온은 켄토를 다이버랜드에 돌려보내고 플러그 잇 할 수 없게 만든 거야뾰꼬.
That's why Gladion sent you back to Diverland and disabled the Plug It.
Itu sebabnya Gladion kembalikan kau ke Diverland dan membuat agar kau tidak bisa Plug It.
날 위해서라니, 글라디온!
Gladion went that far just for me...
Demi aku, Gladion sampai...
켄토 군. 준비 다 됐다. 빨리 글라디온에게 가거라.
Everything's ready, Kento. You can go to Gladion's place now.
Kento, persiapan selesai. Kau bisa pergi ke tempat Gladion secepatnya.
-글라디온이 있는 곳...
-어쩔 거야, 켄토.
-Gladion's place...
-What will you do, Kento?
-Ke tempat Gladion...
-Bagaimana, Kento?
글라디온은 네가 오기를 원하지 않는다고 말했고 네 아빠하고 카이토는 인질이야.
Karon said that Gladion does not want you to come, and your dad and Kaito are taken as hostages.
Karon bilang Gladion tidak ingin kau datang. Lagipula, kau kan tahu Paman dan Kaito sedang disandera.
-켄토.
-Kento.
글라디온은 날 생각해 줬어. 내가 글라디온을 위해 할 수 있는 건...
Gladion thought what's best for me. What I can do in return is..
Gladion telah memikirkan yang terbaik untukku. Yang bisa kulakukan adalah...
박사님! 전송 위치를 바꾸어 주세요!
Professor! Please change the transfer destination!
Profesor! Tolong ganti tujuan pemindahanku, ya!
-전송 위치를? 어디로?
-다이탈리온 안으로요.
-The destination? Where to?
-Inside Ditalion.
-Mengganti tujuan? Kemana?
-Ke dalam Ditalion.
-다이탈리온 안이라고?
-제가 글라디온을 위해 가능한 건
-Inside Ditalion?
-What can I do for Gladion is
-Ke dalam Ditalion?
-Yang bisa kulakukan untuk Gladion adalah
아빠하고 카이토를 구한 다음에 글라디온하고 같이 싸우는 거에요!
to save dad and Kaito first so that he can fight freely as he likes!
menyelamatkan Ayah dan Kaito agar Gladion bisa bertarung dengan bebas!
켄토.
Kento.
조심해라, 켄토. 켄토 군과 글라디온은 우리의 마지막 희망이다.
Be careful, Kento. You and Gladion are our last hope.
Berhati-hatilah, Kento. Kau dan Gladion adalah harapan kami yang terakhir.
네. 얘들아, 나 가 볼게.
Got it. Everyone, I'm going.
Ya. Teman-teman, aku pergi dulu, ya.
잘 갔다오렴, 켄토.
Come back safely, Kento.
Selamat berjuang, Kento.
출발! 전부 준비 완료!
All transfer preparation complete!
Semua persiapan perpindahan selesai!
-네오다이브 시스템 시동!
-시동!
-Neodive System startup!
-Startup!
-Aktifkan Neodive System! Cepat!
-Segera aktifkan!
여기가 다이탈리온 안이라고?
Is this really Ditalion in inside?!
Apa benar ini di dalam tubuhnya Ditalion?!
Brought to you by Subdiver
카론. 여기가 정말 다이탈리온 안 맞아?
Karon, am I really inside Ditalion?
Karon, apa benar ini di dalam Ditalion?
확실히 다이탈리온 안이야뾰꼬.
Yes, you are inside him-pyoko.
Itu memang di dalam Ditalion-pyoko.
몸 가운데에 눈이 내리다니, 대체 뭐야!
How come there be snow fallilng inside a body?! I don't understand this!
Kenapa di dalam tubuh bisa turun salju?! Ini benar-benar aneh!
매지컬 게이트하고 똑 닮은 공간뾰꼬!
I-It's a space that's totally identical with Magical Gate-pyoko!
Dimensi yang benar-benar sama dengan Magical Gate-pyoko!
방금 뭐였지뾰꼬...
What was that just now-pyoko...
Apa itu sebenarnya-pyoko...
-뭐야, 카론?
-잘 모르겠어뾰꼬.
-Is something wrong, Karon?
-I don't know-pyoko.
-Kenapa, Karon?
-Aku tidak mengerti-pyoko.
어쨌든 켄토, 조심해뾰꼬.
Anyway, Kento, be careful-pyoko.
Kau harus hati-hati, Kento-pyoko.
알았어. 꼭 아빠하고 카이토를 찾고 말겠어!
Got it. I will definitely find my dad and Kaito!
Aku mengerti. Pasti akan kutemukan ayah dan Kaito!
글라디온. 좋은 소식을 알려주지. 지금 유우키 켄토는 내 안에 있다.
Gladion, let me tell you a good news. Yuuki Kento is inside me at the moment.
Gladion, ada yang ingin kusampaikan padamu. Saat in Yuuki Kento sedang berada dalam tubuhku.
뭐라고?!
What the?!
Apa?!
움직여 보거라! 움직이면 유우키 켄토에게 목숨은 없다.
Don't move! Move, and I'll take Yuuki Kento's life.
Jangan bergerak! Kalau kau bergerak, nyawa Yuuki Kento akan melayang.
그리고 유우키 켄토의 마음을 발기발기 찢어 보여주지.
And after that, I'll make sure to tear his soul apart.
Dan setelah itu, akan kucabik-cabik jiwa Yuuki Kento.
시간의 신의 힘. 깨닫거라.
I'll make you realize the power of the god of time!
Akan kubuat kau mengerti betapa mengerikannya kekuatan dewa waktu!
이 눈폭풍 어딘가에 아빠하고 카이토가 있어. 찾아내고야 말 거야!
Dad and Kaito must be somewhere inside this snowstorm. I won't give up just yet!
Ayah dan Kaito pasti ada di suatu tempat di tengah badai salju ini. Aku tidak boleh kalah!
저건?
What's that?
Apa itu?
얼음시계...
A clock... made of ice?
Jam bandul... dari es.
어딜 가도 출구가 없구나.
There is no exit wherever we go.
Pergi kemanapun juga tidak ada jalan keluarnya.
지금 이 매지컬 마이트를 사용하면 다이탈리온을 쓰러뜨릴 수 있다.
If I use this Magical Might right now, I'll be able to take Ditalion down.
Kalau sekarang Magical Might ini digunakan, Ditalion pasti bisa dikalahkan.
그래도...
But...
Tapi...
내 자신은 어떻게 되어도 상관 없지만 카이토만은 구하고 싶군.
I don't really care about myself, but Kaito... he must be saved.
Aku tidak peduli bagaimana jadinya aku, tapi Kaito harus diselamatkan.
-아빠! 저거!
-응?
-Dad! Look at that!
-Hm?
-Ayah! Lihat itu!
-Ah?
이건?
What's that?
Apa itu?
아빠!
Daddy!
Ayah!
어떻게든 탈출할 수야 있겠지!
How do we get out from here?
Bagaimana caranya untuk keluar dari sini?
안타깝게도 두 분 다 탈출할 수 없지요.
Unfortunately, both of you won't be able to get out from here forever.
Sayang sekali, kalian berdua tidak bisa keluar dari sini untuk selamanya.
-누구냐?!
-여기야!
-Who was that?!
-Here!
-Siapa itu?!
-Kami di sini!
너희들!
You guys!
Kalian, kan?
같이 따라오시지요.
We need you to follow us.
Kalian harus ikut bersama kami.
켄토네 아버지.
Kento's father.
Ayahnya Kento.
공룡 화석? 이건 또 뭐야? 방금 전만 해도 눈 가득히 떨어졌는데!
Dinosaur fossil? What's going on? It was snow falling all over before!
Kenapa fosil dinosaurus? Kenapa bisa begini? Padahal tadi masih penuh dengan salju!
또 시계...
A clock again...
Lagi-lagi ada jam...
우주?
What, space now?
Luar angkasa?
이번엔 또 어디야?
Where am I this time?
Dimana lagi sekarang?
어라?
That's!
Itu!
아빠! 카이토!
Dad! Kaito!
Ayah! Kaito!
-켄토!
-형!
-Kento!
-Brother!
-Kakak!
카이토! 지금 구하러 갈게!
Kaito! I'm going to save you right now!
Kaito! Aku akan menolongmu!
다이탈리온의 시간의 신전에 온 것을 환영한다.
Welcome to Ditalion's temple of time.
Selamat datang di kuil waktu Ditalion.
시간의 신전? 누구야?
Temple of time? Who was that?
Kuil waktu? Siapa itu?!
쇼우! 츠바사!
Shou! Tsubasa!
끝장을 볼 때가 왔구나, 켄토.
It's finally the time to settle this up, Kento.
Akhirnya tiba juga untuk membuat perhitungan denganmu, Kento.
둘을 구하고 싶다면 우릴 쓰러뜨리면 돼.
If you want to save them, take us down first.
Kalau kau ingin menyelamatkan mereka berdua, kalahkan kami dahulu.
-그런!
-어쨌든!
-No way!
-Let us begin!
-Mana mungkin aku--
-Ayo kita mulai!
일렉트릭 커터!
Electric Lancer!
미라지 소드!
Mirage Sword!
둘다 데리트로스에게 조종당하고 있잖아!
Both of them are still under Deletloss' control!
Keduanya masih ada di bawah kendali Deletloss!
그래도 난 아빠하고 카이토를 꼭 구할 거야!
Even so, I will save my dad and Kaito no matter what!
Tapi, aku pasti akan menyelamatkan Ayah dan Kaito!
켄토.
Kento.
앞으로 30분.
30 minutes remaining.
Tinggal 30 menit lagi.
일렉트릭 커터!
Electric Lancer!
미라지 소드!
Mirage Sword!
-켄토!
-형!
-Kento!
-Brother!
-Kakak!
켄토. 여기까지구나?
Kento, I guess this is it.
Kento, cukup dulu sampai di sini.
바이바이, 켄토.
Bye-bye, Kento.
Selamat tinggal, Kento.
-먹어라!
-Eat this!
-Terima ini!
그란블레이드!
Granblade!
뭐야?!
What the?!
Apa?!
난 아빠하고 카이토를 구할 거야!
I'm going to save my dad and Kaito!
Aku akan menyelamatkan Ayah dan Kaito!
둘 다 미안.
Sorry, both of you.
Maafkan aku, teman-teman.
쇼우. 츠바사. 페가시온과 라이거온으로 돌아가거라!
Shou. Tsubasa. Return to Pegasion and Ligeron at once!
Shou. Tsubasa. Kembalilah ke Pegasion dan Ligeron!
쇼우. 츠바사. 꼭 구해 줄게.
Shou. Tsubasa. I will definitely save you.
Shou. Tsubasa. Kalian pasti akan kuselamatkan.
형!
Brother!
Kakak!
카이토!
Kaito!
형!
Brother!
Kakak!
카이토!
Kaito!
카이토, 미안.
Kaito, I'm sorry.
Maaf, ya, Kaito.
너무 늦었어.
I was too late to come here.
Aku baru bisa datang sekarang.
다 알아. 형이 날 구하기 위해서라면 언제나 최선을 다했을 거라는 걸!
It's okay. I know that you've been fighting all this time to save me!
Tidak apa-apa, Kak. Aku tahu selama ini Kakak selalu berjuang untuk menyelamatkanku!
카이토.
Kaito.
이야기는 카이토에게서 들었어. 켄토. 잘 했어.
I heard everything from Kaito. Good work, Kento.
Aku sudah dengar beritanya dari Kaito. Kento, kau sudah berjuang dengan keras.
켄토.
Kento.
-켄토.
-Kento.
-고맙다, 켄토.
-켄토, 잘 했다.
-Thank you, Kento.
-Kento, Good job.
-Terima kasih, Kento.
-Bagus, Kento. Kau berhasil.
이걸로 네오다이브 시스템을 종료하겠다.
Now I'll send you back using Neodive System.
Sekarang aku akan membawa kalian kembali dengan Neodive System.
유우키 군! 매지컬 마이트를 사용해라!
Yuuki! Use the Magical Might!
Taketo! Pasanglah Magical Might-nya!
-됐습니다.
-카이토, 곧 엄마를 볼 수 있을 거야.
-It's ready.
-Kaito, you're going to meet mother soon.
-Sudah.
-Kaito, sebentar lagi kau bisa bertemu dengan Ibu.
응!
Yay!
Iya!
유우키 켄토. 내 안에서 나가는 걸 두고 보지 않겠다!
Yuuki Kento. I will not allow you to get out from my body!
Yuuki Kento. Kau tidak boleh keluar dari dalam tubuhku!
-뭔 일인가?
-네오다이브 시스템이 기능을 멈췄습니다.
-What's going on?
-Neodive System has stopped working.
-Ada apa?
-Neodive System berhenti berfungsi.
뭐라고? 유우키 군, 탈출을 멈춰라! 작전 중지!
What? Yuuki, the exit is blocked! Cancel the plan!
Apa? Taketo, jalan keluar tertutup! Batalkan rencana!
지금 매지컬 마이트를 작동시킨다면 너희들도 날아가버린다.
If we use Magical Might now, you guys will be flown away!
Kalau Magical Might digunakan sekarang, kalian semua akan ikut meledak!
-대체 뭔 일이래?
-켄토...
-What the heck's going on?
-Kento...
-Kenapa bisa jadi begini?
어떻게 이런... 탈출 방법이 없어졌다니.
This is unbelievable. We lost the only way to get Kento and the others out from there.
Bagaimana ini... kita kehilangan cara untuk mengeluarkan Kento dan yang lainnya.
어떻게 할 수 없어, 할아버지?
Can't you do something, grandpa?
Apa tidak ada yang bisa dilakukan, Kek?
그런!
No way!
Celaka!
가륜!
Garyun!
쟌. 켄토를 구할 방법이 하나 있다.
Jean. There is only one way to save Kento and the others.
Jean. Hanya ada satu cara untuk menyelamatkan Kento dan yang lainnya.
정말, 가륜?
Is that true, Garyun?
Apa itu benar, Garyun?
우리 둘이서 다이탈리온의 몸에 작은 구멍을 내면 된다.
We can open up a small hole on Ditalion's surface together.
Kau dan aku bisa membuat sedikit saja lubang di tubuh Ditalion.
그렇구나!
So I see!
Benar juga!
탈출도 할 수 없고 매지컬 마이트도 사용할 수 없고 어쩌면 좋아?
We can't escape and the Magical Might can't be used. What should we do?
Kita tidak bisa keluar. Magical Might juga tidak bisa digunakan. Kita harus bagaimana?
아빠.
Dad.
Ayah.
-켄토! 나야! 쟌!
-쟌!
-Kento! It's me, Jean!
-Jean!
-Kento, ini aku, Jean!
-나도 있어!
-나오키!
-I'm here too!
-Naoki!
-Aku juga ada!
지금 구하러 갈게, 켄토!
I'm going to save you now, Kento!
Kami datang untuk menyelamatkanmu, Kento!
켄토, 매지컬 마이트를 아주 약하게 켜 봐. 나머지는 우리한테 맡겨.
Kento, use Magical Might with minimum output. After that, leave the rest to us.
Kento, gunakan Magical Might dengan kekuatan terendah. Setelah itu, serahkan pada kami, ya?
알았어.
Got it.
Aku mengerti.
이렇게 유우키 켄토는 갇혔다. 어쩔 테냐, 글라디온?
Yuuki Kento will be trapped inside forever. What will you do, Gladion?
Akhirnya, Yuuki Kento pun sudah ada di tanganku. Bagaimana, Gladion?
뭐야?
What the?
Apa?
저건!
That's!
Itu!
-켄토 저기!
-비켜! 글라디온!
-Kento's there!
-Get out of the way, Gladion!
-Kento ada di situ!
-Minggir, Gladion!
-가륜!
-샤이닝 어택!
-Garyun!
-Shining Attack!
나는 시간의 신. 그 정도의 공격으로는 달라질 바 없다!
I am the god of time. Such attack won't even make a scratch!
Aku adalah dewa waktu. Serangan seperti ini tidak mempan terhadapku!
-가륜!
-대단한 놈이군.
-Garyun!
-What a power.
-Makhluk macam apa dia?
가륜의 샤이닝 어택이 효과가 없다니...
Garyun's Shining Attack didn't have any effect on him...
Bahkan Shining Attack milik Garyun pun tidak mempan...
켄토! 지금이야!
Kento! Right now!
Kento! Sekarang!
뭐야?!
What is this?!
Apa?!
-켄토!
-걱정하게 해서 미안, 글라디온! 그래도 나...
-Kento!
-I'm sorry for making you worried, Gladion! But I had to...
-Maaf sudah membuatmu cemas, Gladion. Tapi aku...
알고 있어, 켄토.
I know, Kento.
Aku mengerti, Kento.
-그럼 하자! 글라디온!
-그래!
-Then let's do it! Gladion!
-Got it!
-Kita bertempur, Gladion!
-Iya!
웹다이브! 글라디온!
Webdive! Gladion!
네이놈, 유우키 켄토, 글라디온!
Curse you, Yuuki Kento and Gladion!
Kurang ajar kalian! Yuuki Kento! Gladion!
Screenplay
Maeyamada Ken'ichi
Storyboarding
Matsui Hitoyuki
Staging
Katou Shigeru
Voice Actor
Yuuki Kento
Kobayashi Yumiko
Gladion
Sugita Tomokazu
Arisugawa Aoi
Kikuchi Shiho
Asaba Naoki
Takeuchi Junko
Karon
Kaida Yuki
Voice Actor
Jean J. Jekyll
Nakai Masataka
Yuuki Kaito
Takagi Reiko
Yuuki Taketo
Ookura Masaaki
Yuuki Natsuko
Kawasaki Eriko
Arisugawa Professor
Tobita Nobuo
Kurachi Rena
Kakazu Yumi
Hara Tsubasa
Itou Miyako
Voice Actor
Garyuun
Konishi Katsuyuki
Dragwon
Kawada Shinji
Ending Theme
Lyrics
Oikawa Neko
Composer
Suzuki Kisaburo
Arranger
Kouno Yougo
Singer
Kageyama Hironobu
Columbia Japan
Production Cooperation
Animation Production
AEON (We've)
Subtitle
Subdiver
ファン字幕
サブダイバー
Production
Thank you for watching!
Preview for Next Episode
다이버랜드 소멸까지 10분.
10 minutes until Diverland disappears.
Tinggal 10 menit lagi hingga Diverland musnah.
아직이야. 아직 끝이 아니야!
Not yet. It's not the end yet!
Belum. Ini belum berakhir!
내가 절박할 때 도와주러 온 쟌과 가륜.
Jean and Garyuun, together with Naoki and Dragwon
Jean dan Garyuun, serta Naoki dan Dragwon
나오키와 드라그온. 모두의 힘을 합친다면,
who have come to help me. With everyone's power combined,
yang telah datang menolongku. Dengan menyatukan kekuatan kami semua,
어떤 적이라도 쓰러뜨릴 수 있을 거야!
we will be able to take every enemy down!
kami pasti bisa mengalahkan musuh seperti apapun!
전뇌모험기 웹다이버의 다음 이야기!
Next episode of Dennou Boukenki Webdiver!
Di episode Dennou Boukenki Webdiver selanjutnya!
Thanks for watching! - Subdiver
See you at http://subdiver.soreepeong.com/ !